<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<forms>
    <form id="rights_and_responsibilities_1">
        <title>
            Participant’s Rights and Responsibilities Form
        </title>

        <kinyarwanda_title>

        </kinyarwanda_title>

        <body>
            <p>
                As a participant in the NHI program, it is my responsibility to:
            </p>
            <ul>
                <li>
                    Take my ARV medications every day (or as prescribed by
                    my Doctor).
                </li>
                <li>
                    Use A-Heza, provided by the program, for my child who is
                    also in the program. I understand that I will not sell
                    the A-Heza portion I receive.
                </li>
                <li>
                    Provide up to date and important health information to
                    my doctor.
                </li>
                <li>
                    Not mislead or provide false information to staff or
                    volunteers.
                </li>
                <li>
                    Treat all staff and volunteers of the program with respect.
                </li>
                <li>
                    To attend CNPB at least 10 times a year.
                </li>
                <li>
                    To participate in the Farming and Women Artisan
                    Cooperatives.
                </li>
                <li>
                    If I am unable to complete the above listed participant
                    responsibilities, I understand that I will receive a
                    warning. Two warnings will result in removal from the
                    program and I understand that I will not be able to receive
                    more A-Heza.
                </li>
            </ul>
            <p>
                As a participant in the NHI program, I can expect:
            </p>
            <ul>
                <li>
                    To have 1 counseling session as I begin the NHI program.
                </li>
                <li>
                    To have 1 counseling session as I complete the program.
                </li>
                <li>
                    To have access to A-Heza each month. After I deliver my
                    child until they are 6 months, I will receive 8Kgs
                    of A-Heza.
                </li>
                <li>
                    From the time my child is 6 months to 18 months of age I
                    will receive 12 Kgs of A-Heza per month for us both.
                </li>
                <li>
                    From the time my child is 18 months to 24 months of age,
                    only my child will receive 8 Kgs of A-Heza each month.
                </li>
                <li>
                    To be told my baby’s nutritional status each monthly
                    meeting (including weight, height and zone of nutrition)
                </li>
                <li>
                    That my HIV status will be kept confidential
                </li>
                <li>
                    To be treated with respect by all TIP staff and volunteers
                </li>
                <li>
                    To have access to TIP staff in the event that I have a
                    concern about the program and my participation
                </li>
                <li>
                    To be able to speak with staff about findings of health
                    indicators assessed during the health assessments and any
                    techniques used to determine those indicators.
                </li>
            </ul>
        </body>

        <kinyarwanda_body>

        </kinyarwanda_body>
    </form>

    <form id="grievance_procecdure_1">
        <title>
            Prenatal and Post Partum Participant Grievance Procedure
        </title>

        <kinyarwanda_title>

        </kinyarwanda_title>

        <body>
            <p>
                TIP believes in giving participants second chances and in
                making changes to our program to better serve our participants.
                The Eheza App Project is dedicated to providing the highest
                quality of services to our participants. We believe that to
                accomplish this, we must provide them with a method of
                addressing issues and/or concerns that cannot be resolved
                informally between TIP participants and staff.
            </p>

            <h2>What is a Grievance?</h2>

            <p>
                A grievance is a formal expression of concern about any
                particular issue thought to be unjust, unfair or abusive.
                Filing a grievance means putting in writing anything that
                you have experienced that you believe was harmful or unfair.
                You have the right to file a grievance at any time without
                fear of retaliation.
            </p>

            <h2>Formal Grievance Procedures</h2>

            <p>
                <b>Step 1.</b> If for any reason a TIP participant feels
                she/he has not been treated well or fairly or has not received
                the service expected, that participant can address their grievance
                in writing to the Community Health Worker responsible for their case.
            </p>

            <p>
                <b>Step 2.</b> Should the participant not receive complete
                satisfaction after addressing the staff person directly,
                or if they feel uncomfortable addressing that person,
                the client is encouraged to address the Hospital Director
                with their written complaint.
            </p>

            <p>
                <b>Step 3.</b> Following this course, should no satisfaction be
                attained with the Hospital Director, the participant may contact
                the US-based team via email or by phone.
            </p>

            <p>
                <b>Step 4.</b> The participant can expect their grievance to be
                addressed and resolved in a under one month
            </p>

            <p>
                <b>Step 5.</b> Upon final resolution of the grievance issue,
                the appropriate TIP staff will propose a summary of the issue,
                ultimate resolution, and the action plan to prevent repeat occurrences.
            </p>
        </body>

        <kinyarwanda_body>

        </kinyarwanda_body>
    </form>
</forms>
